In fact, we operate in a world of prejudice.
実際、私たちは偏見の世界で生きています。
And there, we're going to learn little by little, because we're going to open our eyes wider,
そして今から、私たちは少しずつ学んでいきます。なぜなら、視野を広げるからです。
it's about living with our eyes a little more open.
それは、もう少し目を開いて生きることです。
Learning to identify our own patterns.
私たち自身のパターンを見つけることを学ぶ。
And I'm going to suggest that you observe a pattern.
そして、あるパターンを観察することを提案します。
And if you manage to observe it,
そして、もしあなたがそれを観察できるなら、
you can...
あなたは...
Most of the time, we use others as
ほとんどの場合、私たちは他人を〜として利用します。
our own rags to clean our own windows.
私たち自身の窓を拭くための雑巾として。
Have you ever noticed that in your patterns, you
あなたは、あなたのパターンの中に、
have to see this,
それを見る必要があることに、気づきましたか？
that we project our patterns of satisfaction
私たちが満足のパターンを
outside of ourselves?
私たちの外側に投影していることに？
on a subject or an object.
ある主題やある対象に。
And then, in fact, one day, we are disappointed.
そして、実際、ある日、私たちは失望します。
It no longer satisfies me.
それはもう私を満足させません。
What's important is that at some point,
重要なのは、ある時点で、
we resent the other.
私たちは相手を恨むということです。
We'll understand.
理解しましょう。
Suddenly, I resent the other.
突然、私は相手を恨みます。
And some go even further.
そして、中にはさらに進む人もいます。
When we've projected too much outside of ourselves,
私たちが私たちの外側に過度に投影しすぎたとき、
we even resent the world.
私たちは世界さえも恨みます。
So it's about observing.
だから、それは観察することです。
identify our own patterns.
私たち自身のパターンを見つけること。
One way to achieve this,
それを達成する方法の一つは、
is to meditate.
瞑想することです。
If you want to discover your mind,
もしあなたが自分の心を発見したいなら、
You do an exercise, you'll see
エクササイズをしてみてください、そうすればわかるでしょう。
that after 7 seconds,
7秒後には、
there will be
何かが生じるでしょう
thoughts that will arise.
思考が湧き上がってくるでしょう。
And suddenly, you are caught
そして突然、あなたは引き込まれます
by a thought.
ある思考に。
And meditation,
そして瞑想とは、
it consists of observing that and coming back.
それを観察し、戻ってくることです。
And the act of learning to observe something neutral
そして、中立的なものを観察することを学ぶという行為は
teaches you little by little to discover your own patterns which are not neutral.
あなた自身の、中立ではないパターンを徐々に発見することを教えます。
So there's work and a study of yourself, if you will.
ですから、もしあなたが望むなら、自己の探求と研究があるのです。
What do you feel when you see?
あなたは見たときに何を感じますか？
It's immediate, it's passive.
それは即座であり、受動的です。
You open your eyes and suddenly the world is there.
目を開けると、突然世界がそこにある。
And often we think that seeing is believing.
そしてしばしば、見ることは信じることだと私たちは考えます。
I believe because I saw.
私は見たから信じる。
So we think that vision is truth.
だから、視覚が真実だと私たちは考えます。
Learning to understand.
理解することを学ぶ。
What we see is not in fact a universal truth.
私たちが見ているものは、実際には普遍的な真実ではありません。
It is not a so-called objective reality.
それは客観的と呼ばれる現実ではありません。
When you work, we have prejudices.
あなたが作業するとき、私たちは偏見を持っています。
And that's what needs to be understood.
そして、これを理解する必要があります。
Because nature doesn't know how to take prejudices into account.
なぜなら、自然は偏見を考慮に入れることができないからです。
The therapeutic process doesn't take that into account, in fact.
治療プロセスは、実際にはそれを考慮に入れません。
These are brakes, false fulcrums.
それはブレーキであり、誤ったもの、そして支点です。
We create a virtual reality, if you will, and we think it's unique.
もしあなたが望むなら、私たちは仮想現実を創造し、それを唯一のものだと考えます。
You should know that your visual cortex uses 30% of the mind.
あなたの視覚野が脳の処理能力の30%を使用していることを知る必要があります。
your brain, 30%, compared to touch
あなたの脳の30%が、触覚と比較して
which is 8% and hearing which is only 2-3%.
触覚が8%、聴覚がわずか2-3%であるのと比べて。
Every second, your eyes are capable of sending about
毎秒、あなたの目は約
2 billion pieces of information
20億の情報を
to your visual cortex, 2 billion.
あなたの視覚野に送ることができます、20億です。
The rest of your body can only send about a billion.
あなたの体の残りの部分は約10億しか送ることができません。
that means that sight will represent
それは視覚が占めることになります。
one third
3分の1
of your brain volume
あなたの脳の容積の。
and yet it will use
しかしながら、それは使用します。
two thirds of your resources
あなたのリソースの3分の2を。
it's not surprising after all
結局、それは驚くことではありません。
that it's an illusion if it's so important
それほど重要であるならば、それが幻想であることは。
if I tell you the Papez circuit
もし私がパペッツ回路について話すとしたら、
does that mean anything to you
何か思い当たりますか？
all the colliculi and all the amygdaloid
全ての視蓋と全ての核、
nuclei etc. that will integrate
扁桃体などが統合される。
everything you see
あなたが見る全ては、
influences your emotions.
あなたの感情に影響を与えます。
And your emotions can change what you see.
そしてあなたの感情は、あなたが見るものを変えることができます。
So that means that sight will become a mental composition.
ですから、視覚は精神的な構成物になるということです。
We create our own reality.
私たち自身の現実を創造します。
And what's more, we believe it.
そしてさらに、私たちはそれを信じます。
So that means it's just one way of forming a reality.
ですから、それは現実を形成するための単なる方法であるということです。
For example, fear, have you ever noticed
例えば、恐怖が、あなたはすでに気づきましたか？
how it can distort reality.
どのように現実を歪めることができるかを。
I had a child.
ある子供がいました。
like that who came, he was traumatized. They had seen a movie.
そのようにやって来た彼は、トラウマを負っていました。彼らは映画を見ていました。
It's that he associated being
それは彼が関連付けたことです。
scared and being in danger. And in fact, the only thing I
怖がることと危険にさらされることを。そして実際、私がした唯一のことは、
did was dissociate. I said,
それを切り離すことでした。私は言いました、
you were scared, you were afraid, you were scared. But
「君は怖がった、恐怖を感じた、怖がった。しかし、
I said, but you're not in danger.
私は言います、君は危険ではない。」
I saw it suddenly.
私はそれを突然見ました。
His reality readjusted, you see.
その実在は再調整されるのです。
And so once you dissociate things again, they fade away, you see.
ですから、これを再認識すると、物事は消え去るのです。
Because nothing has its own existence.
なぜなら、何ものも固有の存在を持たないからです。
Do you understand that?
これをご理解いただけますか？
Nothing exists by itself.
何ものもそれ自体では存在しません。
When we understand that, we have a changing view.
これを理解すると、私たちの視点は変化します。
Because that means we can understand that even the ego does not exist by itself.
なぜなら、それはエゴでさえそれ自体では存在しないことを理解できるからです。
It becomes a...
それは一つの...
aggregate, it shows that everything is interdependent and impermanent.
集合体であり、全てが相互依存的で無常であることを示しています。
And impermanence is what
そして無常なものこそが、
gives energy, because it gives movement. So it gives your
エネルギーを与えます。なぜなら、それが動きを与えるからです。つまり、それはあなたの
vital energy in fact. It's
生命エネルギーなのです。それは
the chi, since it's a change
気（チー）です。なぜなら、それは常に変化するものであり、
all the time. So in fact, if we want to work on that, we must
常に。ですから、もし私たちがこれに取り組みたいなら、私たちは
impermanence. So to open our vision, we must
無常性（を理解すること）です。さて、私たちの視野を広げるためには、
be truly attentive to every moment,
あらゆる瞬間に真に注意を払う必要があります。
to every thought, to every detail. That means we must learn to see beyond
あらゆる思考に、あらゆる細部に。それは、私たちの
our
投影や
projections, beyond our fears. That's where we must little by little learn to
恐怖の向こう側を見ることを学ぶ必要があるということです。そこでは、私たちは徐々に
free ourselves from our
私たちの誤った解釈から解放されることを学ぶ必要があります。
false interpretations. It's not easy.
それは容易ではありません。
Because sometimes, we even want to remain fixed in our ideology.
なぜなら、時として私たちは自分のイデオロギーに固執したいとさえ思うからです。
So, it's not complicated.
さて、それは複雑ではありません。
As soon as you think you're in reality, you're wrong.
現実にいると思った瞬間、あなたは間違っています。
What I propose to you is to increasingly exploit your inner strength.
私が提案するのは、ますますあなたの内なる力を活用することです。
Exploit, readjust your ideas about luck and success.
運と成功に関するあなたの考えを活用し、再調整してください。
Have the right intention.
正しい意図を持つことです。
This morning, I expressed something to you. We're going to work with your
今朝、私はあなた方に何かを伝えました。私たちはあなたの
center of gravity,
重心、
your whole body, at the service of your hands. The vital energy is
あなたの全身を、あなたの手のために使います。生命エネルギーは、
in the belly.
腹部にあります。
It's one of the important centers. This impermanence supports
それは重要な中心の一つです。この無常が支えています。
this vital energy.
この生命エネルギーを。
So if you could gradually adjust yourself,
もし徐々に、本当にご自身を調整できるようになれば、
With your own center, it will be much more powerful, surprisingly.
ご自身の中心と調和することで、驚くほどはるかに強力になるでしょう。
And you could feel a little this morning, when I asked you to adjust yourself.
今朝、ご自身を調整するようにお願いした時、少し感じられたことでしょう。
I did it, I made you adjust, you just have to adjust.
私が調整を促しました。ただ調整すれば良いのです。
Because we're going to work with three main types of energy, three main types of movement.
なぜなら、私たちは3つの主要なエネルギーのタイプ、3つの主要な動きのタイプを用いて作業するからです。
We're going to work with induced movement, we're going to work with permitted movement,
私たちは誘導された動き、許容された動きと共に作業します。
and we're going to work with present movement.
そして、現在の動きと共に作業します。
I can induce something.
私は何かを誘導することができます。
I must do it consciously.
私はそれを意識的に行わなければなりません。
Or I can follow something.
あるいは、私は何かに従うことができます。
Or I can just listen to the present moment.
あるいは、ただ今この瞬間に耳を傾けることができます。
So it's accepting your strength, accepting your weakness.
つまり、自分の強さを受け入れ、自分の弱さを受け入れることです。
And also understanding the difference between that.
そして、それらの違いも理解することです。
And opening your heart to these countless possibilities that are
そして、そこにある無数の可能性に心を開くことです。
there.
そこにある。
Often...
しばしば...
When I have people like that who come with quite acute problems,
このような人々がかなり急性な問題を抱えて来る時、
not with small, quite acute, depressive, quite deep problems, things
小さな問題ではなく、かなり急性で、抑うつ的で、かなり根深い、
like that,
そのようなことの場合、
I ask them a question, I say, "When you're healed, what will you be able to do?"
私は彼らに質問をします。「ねえ、治癒したら、何ができるようになるだろう？」と。
What will you be able to do again?
何が再びできるようになるだろうか？
It's a whole new program that sometimes they hadn't even thought about.
それは、時には彼らが考えもしなかった、まったく新しいプログラムなのです。
It's important, because you create a direction.
それは重要です。なぜなら、方向性を生み出すからです。
And that's it, you have to work with health.
そして、それが健康と共に働くということです。
We should not work with illness or against illness, we should work
病気と共に、あるいは病気に対抗して働くべきではありません。私たちは働くべきです。
with health.
健康と共に。
And so sometimes this passage is very narrow, directing our attention towards
したがって、時にはこの道筋は非常に狭く、私たちの注意を〜に向ける必要があります。
health.
健康。